<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ScrollView xmlns:android="http://schemas.android.com/apk/res/android"
    xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools"
    android:layout_width="match_parent"
    android:layout_height="match_parent"
    android:paddingBottom="@dimen/activity_vertical_margin"
    android:paddingLeft="@dimen/activity_horizontal_margin"
    android:paddingRight="@dimen/activity_horizontal_margin"
    android:paddingTop="@dimen/activity_vertical_margin"
    tools:context="com.tanvi.myway.ten"
    android:background="#fffefe">
    <RelativeLayout

        android:layout_width="wrap_content"
        android:layout_height="match_parent"
        >

        <TextView
        android:layout_width="wrap_content"
        android:layout_height="wrap_content"
        android:textAppearance="?android:attr/textAppearanceMedium"
        android:id="@+id/textView22"
        android:layout_alignParentLeft="true"
        android:layout_alignParentStart="true"
        android:text="\n \nLaws regarding Road traffic accidents:          \n\n1. According to a Supreme Court Judgement, an accident victim is entitled to immediate emergency medical care.           \n\n2. A doctor is duty bound to provide primary care to the patient and informing the police is the hospital’s responsibility.           \n\n3. In the case of an accident the police will be called by the hospital, while they file medicolegal cases.           \n\n4. If the hospital is not equipped to handle the patient’s injuries, it is the hospital’s responsibility to stabilize the patient and provide an ambulance to be transferred to another better equipped hospital.           \n\n5. The hospital also has no right to delay first aid or life saving measures on the basis of procedural delays for reasons such as absence of a relative to sign forms etc.           \n\n6. It is mandated by the Supreme court order under the Motor vehicles act 1988 (sec 134), that the primary duty of the driver of the vehicle involved in the accident is to take the injured to the hospital. The only exception to this rule is that if the driver of the vehicle himself is grievously injured. He must answer all questions asked by the police and submit to tests that are required. He must provide the police and the victim with his insurance details, to help with the payment of any damages. \n\n7. If the person does not comply with any of these laws, he/she liable to be punishable with a jail sentence of 3 months and a fine of 1000 rupees.   \n\nHelp in Road Accidents:  \n \nHelping road accident victims will now become free of legal and procedural hassles as the Supreme Court on 2014 directed the Centre to come up with a legal framework in three months to enact a Good Samaritan law so that road accident fatalities can be reduced by providing victims proper emergency care in time. \n\nIndia tops the list of deaths caused by road accidents. According to a data released by the Ministry of Road Transport and Highways in 2013, around 1,37,576 people lost their lives in road accidents. The number translates into 380 deaths per day.  \n\nOn the recommendations of a court-appointed panel, the Ministry of Home Affairs (MHA) has issued following guidelines for protection of Good Samaritans: \n\ni. If a person, who is not an eyewitness, moves an injured person to the nearest hospital, he or she should not be questioned and be allowed to leave immediately.  \n\nii. Good Samaritans should be exempted from civil and criminal liability, except in case of malafides.  \n\niii. Those who inform the police or emergency services about a person lying injured on the road should not be forced to reveal their identity and personal details.  \n\niv. Personal information such as name and contact details of those who come forward for the help of road crash victims will be voluntary and optional, including in the Medico Legal Case (MLC) forms provided by hospitals.  \n\nv. In case a person, who has voluntarily stated that he or she is an eye witness to the accident is required to be questioned for the purpose of investigation but the questioning will take only once. \n\nvi. Standard operating procedures will be developed in 60 days to ensure that the rescuer is not harassed, intimidated or hassled by the police or courts.Technology, such as video conferencing, should be used to examine a witness.  \n\nvii. All registered public and private hospitals cannot detain or demand money for registration and admission of the injured unless the person who has brought the victim is his or her relative.  \n\nviii. The injured should be provided necessary treatment without delay. All hospitals designate a minimum of 2 percent of its annual profits towards free treatment on injured.  \n\nix. Lack of response by a doctor in an emergency situation pertaining to road accidents, where he may be reasonably expected to provide care, shall constitute “professional misconduct” under chapter 7 of the Code of Ethics Regulations, 2002 of the Medical Council of India. Suitable disciplinary action will be taken as per the norms of Chapter 8 of the said regulations.  \n\nx. All public and private hospitals will implement these directions within a period of 60 days from the date when these directions are issued. In case of non-compliance or violation of the directions within the time prescribed, the licenses issued to operate these hospitals shall stand revoked.    \n\nLaw relating to Pedestrian \n\nA. Indian law under the Motor Vehicle Act, 1988 and other related act provide for preventing the vehicles to run on footpaths. \n\n-There are several Acts that safeguard pedestrian rights indirectly. \n\nB. The Indian Penal Code (1860) sections 279[1], 304 (Punishment for Culpable Homicide not Amounting to Murder), and 336[2]/337/338 protects the public, which includes pedestrians, against rash driving and negligence by motorists.\n\nC. The Motor Vehicles Act (1988), sections 7-38 talks about penalizing the motorists exceeding speed limits and license regulation etc, indirectly protecting vulnerable road users. \n\nD.Section 138 clause empowers the State government to prevent motor vehicles from using the pavements for driving or parking.  \n\nE. The Rules of the Road Regulation (1989) has three rules mentioning pedestrians or their right of way, which are:  \n-The duty of the driver to slow down when approaching a pedestrian crossing (Rule 8) \n-That no driver can park a motor vehicle near a traffic light or on a pedestrian crossing or a footpath (Rule \n-Motor vehicles are not allowed to drive on the footpaths or cycle lane except with permission from the police officer on duty (Rule 11)   \n\nLegal Process after car accident: \n\n1) section 279 IPC deals with rash and negligent driving punishable with imprisonment upto 6 months or fine up to Rs 1000 or both  \n\n2) it is also punishable under section 336 , 337, 338 of IPC which provide that if person drives rashly endangering life or personal liberty of others . under section 338 IPC punishable with imprisonment of up  to  2 years or with fine or both  \n\n3) if the victim dies police will file case under section 304A if death arise on account of rash and negligent act  \n\n4) prosecution has to prove that car  or vehicle was driven in rash and negligent manner   \n\n5) The car owner can be liable if the car was not in roadworthy condition.He should have  proper documents including insurance cover - The driver employed is experienced enough to handle the model or type of vehicle besides having a valid driving license  \n\n6) the insurance company takes liability if car is insured .It is for the insurer to proceed against the insured for recovery of the amount in the event there has been violation of any condition of the insurance policy \n\n7) Section 145 to 164 of the Act provides for mandatory third party insurance, which is compulsory for a vehicle owner. This means that if you have a vehicle that you use to move in public places, you cannot do so legally unless you have an insurance policy. Typically, your insurance policy papers must always be kept in the car with your car registration and driving licence. \n\n8) Section 146(1) of the Act prohibits a vehicle owner from using the vehicle in a public place without undertaking an insurance policy in compliance with the Act.  \n\n\n(Source: http://www.firstpost.com/india/want-help-accident-victims-scared-law-fear-1783297.html \n https://www.kaanoon.com/indian-law/indian-penal-code/ \n http://lawisgreek.com/indian-laws-motor-vehicle-accident-claims/"
            android:typeface="serif"
            android:textColor="#050000" />

        <TextView
            android:layout_width="wrap_content"
            android:layout_height="wrap_content"
            android:textAppearance="?android:attr/textAppearanceLarge"
            android:text="Indian Laws for Road Accidents:"
            android:id="@+id/textView20"
            android:layout_alignParentTop="true"
            android:textColor="#06731a"
            android:typeface="normal"
            android:layout_alignParentLeft="true"
            android:layout_alignParentStart="true"
            android:textStyle="bold" />
    </RelativeLayout>
</ScrollView>